Guide to the Center For Student Life Records RG.12.16
New York University Archives
Center for Student Life Records
1958-2018
New York University Archives
New York University. Center for Student Life
Vogelsang, David
RG.12.16
7.4 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes, 7 flat boxes, 1 record carton, 1 CD box, and 1 oversized flat box
2.05 Gigabytes in 14 computer files
The Center for Student Life Records contain paper and electronic records of student publications; fliers; event posters and calendars; photographs; brochures; guides for campus programs for incoming students; and programs from the Office of Student Activities. These materials reflect the social lives of the students at New York University through events and programs sponsored by student-led organizations, lecture series, and sororities and fraternities. The Center for Student Life assists New York University students in fostering a sense of community and supports students' transition into campus life.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by David Vogelsang, Executive Director, Center for Student Life in May 2018. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.016. An additional accretion of materials was donated by David Vogelsang, Executive Director, Center for Student Life, in September 2018. The accession number associated with the accretion is 2019.010.
Arrangement
The series and subseries arrangement of the records is as follows:
Series I. 2018 Donation, 1958-2018
Series II. 2019 Accretion, 1992-2018
Subseries II.A Events, 1996-2017 Subseries II.B Programs, 1993-2018 Subseries II.C Publications, 1992-2010 Series I was not arranged by an archivist; materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor. Series II is arranged into three subseries alphabetically. The files within each subseries are arranged chronologically by year.
Historical Note
The Center for Student Life engages New York University students during their transition into campus life. The Center serves as a central point of information and campus-wide events, and helps students navigate various aspects of the university, including clubs, fraternities, sororities, class activities boards, and community service opportunities.
Custodial History
This collection was created and stored in the Center for Student Life. Various administrators and employees in the office collected the items. The majority of the items were collected by Bob Butler, former director of the Center for Student Life, but others may have also contributed to the collection.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Scope and Contents
The Center for Student Life Records (1958-2018) contain paper and electronic records of student publications; fliers; event posters and calendars; photographs; brochures; guides for campus programs for incoming students; and programs from the Office of Student Activities. These materials reflect the social lives of the students at New York University through events and programs sponsored by student-led organizations, lecture series, and sororities and fraternities. The 2019 accretion consists of event posters, conference programs, and flyers for concerts sponsored by NYU's Program Board; celebrations such as Pride Month and Asian Heritage Month; and student organization-sponsored events for groups such as La Herencia Latina and the Korean Student Association. Additionally, it includes programs and information bulletins on clubs, alternative spring breaks, Greek organizations, and the GOLD Leadership Program from the Office of Student Activities. Also included are student and university publications, such as The Minetta Review, The Plague, and Humanus: The New York University Journal of Human Rights.
Student activities.; Pamphlets.; College students -- New York (N.Y.); Education, Higher.; Programs (documents); College student newspapers and periodicals.; Periodicals; Posters.; Fliers (printed matter); Vogelsang, David; New York University -- Students; Stevens, Sufjan; Birbiglia, Mike; Jett, Joan
- Series I. 2018 Donation, 1958-2018; 2.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 1 manuscript box, and 1 flat box
  Scope and Contents
  The original 2018 donation mostly includes program guides for such as events as the President's Service Award ceremonies, parent activities, and student orientations from 1989 to 2018. Additionally, there is an album from 1958 and memorabilia from 1988-2010.
  - Memorabilia, 1988-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1-4, Box 3, Folder 1, Folder 3)
  - Album 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - All in a Lifetime, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Program guides, 1991-2018 (Box 1, Folder 7-13, Box 2, Folder 1-8, Box 3, Folder 2)
- Series II. 2019 Accretion, 1992-2018; 4.9 Linear Feet in 6 flat boxes, 6 manuscript boxes, 1 CD box, and 1 oversized flat box; 2.05 Gigabytes in 14 computer files
  The 2019 accretion consists of event posters, conference programs, and flyers for concerts sponsored by NYU's Program Board; celebrations such as Pride Month and Asian Heritage Month; and student organization-sponsored events for groups such as La Herencia Latina and the Korean Student Association. Additionally, it includes programs and information bulletins on clubs, alternative spring breaks, Greek organizations, and the GOLD Leadership Program from the Office of Student Activities. Also included are student and university publications, such as The Minetta Review, The Plague, and Humanus: The New York University Journal of Human Rights. Additionally, Subseries I contains original student artwork, presumably for event posters; signed performance posters by reputable artists, such as musicians Sufjan Stevens and Joan Jett in addition to the comedian Mike Birbiglia; audio files from unknown musical events; and digital photographs from a Martin Luther King, Jr., Day celebration.
  - Subseries II.A Events, 1996-2017
    - Posters, 1996; cuid18103 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Posters, 1997; cuid18104 (Box 10, Folder 2, Box Shared University Archives 005, Folder 5)
    - Programs and Flyers, 1997-1999; cuid18105 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Posters, 1998; cuid18106 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Musical Event Audio Files, 1999; cuid18107 (Box Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_12_16_ER_1)
    - Posters, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 4, Box Shared University Archives 005, Folder 5)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2000; cuid18108 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Posters, 2000; cuid18109 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2001; cuid18110 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Posters, 2001; cuid18111 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2002; cuid18112 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Posters, 2002; cuid18113 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2003; cuid18114 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Posters, 2003; cuid18115 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2004; cuid18116 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Posters, 2004; cuid18117 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2005; cuid18118 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Posters, 2005; cuid18119 (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
    - Photographs of Martin Luther King, Jr., Day Event, 2006; cuid18120 (Box Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_12_16_ER_3)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Posters, 2006; cuid18121 (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2007; cuid18122 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Posters, 2007; cuid18123 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2008; cuid18124 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Posters, 2008; cuid18125 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2009; cuid18126 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Posters, 2009; cuid18127 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2010; cuid18128 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Posters, 2010; cuid18129 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2011; cuid18130 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Posters, 2011; cuid18131 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Posters, 2012; cuid18132 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Programs and Flyers, 2012-2013; cuid18133 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Flyers, 2017; cuid18134 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Musical Event Audio Files, undated; cuid18135 (Box Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_12_16_ER_2)
    - Programs and Flyers, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Posters, undated; cuid18136 (Box 15, Folder 3-5)
    - Student Artwork (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Subseries II.B Programs, 1993-2018
    - Programs, 1993-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Programs, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Programs, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Programs, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Programs, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Programs, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Programs, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Programs, 2007-2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Programs, 2008-2010 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Programs, 2011-2018 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Programs, undated (Box 6, Folder 4, Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II.C Publications, 1992-2010
    - Publications, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Publications, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Publications, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Publications, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Publications, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Publications, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Publications, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Publications, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Publications, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Publications, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Publications, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - Publications, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 1-2, Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Publications, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Publications, 2009-2010 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Publications, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)